

# AK AJAYKUMARK



ash1141wanth@gmail.com



+91 9442495306



Kanyakumari District, Tamil nadu - 629161

## **Summary**

A Meticulous Software Engineer with 5 years of work experience in the Information Technology and Services Industry. Strong conceptual thinker with good interpersonal skills who aligns with teams to achieve strategic business objectives. Looking for a better opportunity, specifically on the Data science domain to improvise my skills effectively for personal growth and for the betterment of the organization.

#### Skills

- Have good hold on Python, SQL, with more focus on ML libraries such as Numpy, Pandas, Matplot & Sckit.
- Data Manipulation, Data Wrangling and Data Visualization techniques.
- Managing Machine learning models in production.
- Defining requirements, testing & Deployment.
- Fluency with CI/CD tools (Git, Jira, etc.)
- Exposure on both Azure and AWS cloud platforms
- Proficient in working with Agile & DevOps Methodologies.

# **Professional Experience**

Technology Analyst / Infosys Ltd- Trivandrum, Kerala

05/2018 - Current

Current Project:

Client: Nike | Team: Digital Demand Sensing

01/2020 - Current

Working with a high impact Data science team (R&D/Operations) which plays a major role in the overall productivity of Nike. We rely on a set of data science tools and Machine learning models to predict the future production demand of products. The curated prediction numbers were sent as a final signal to the physical production units. Used Data analysis and visualization techniques to solve data related problems and presented them as Proof of Concepts. Implemented functions that reduced external file dependencies for the ETL processes.

#### **Job Duties:**

- Run ETL process to extract historical sales data from multiple data sources and combine them into single data set.
- Perform Data cleansing, Data Normalization, Feature Engineering to enrich the data.
- Feed the data to Machine learning model, train them for each submit gates to generate forecast for a future target season.
- Tune the hyperparameters if needed to enhance the forecast accuracy rate.
- Perform data validation and visualize the data.
- Analyze the client requirements and present the POC.
- Perform code changes/enhancements through CI/CD, in line with the Agile methodology.

- Engage in all stages of SDLC. Perform code reviews adhering to standard coding practices.
- Optimize the code & processes to enhance the performance.
- Schedule the repetitive processes using Job schedulers (Luigi/ Airflow).

**Skills Acquired**: Python, XGBoost, Decision trees, Data Analysis, Machine Learning, Statistical Modelling, Data Engineering, Asp .Net, Snowflake, Git, Jira, Azure, AWS S3, Airflow.

#### • Previous Project:

#### Client : Truist Bank | Team: Private Wealth Management

05/2018 - 12/2019

Managed few mainframe applications that takes care of Investment Banking related transactions through nightly batches. Majorly worked on resolving issues, identifying and rectifying code defects through Changes/Problem tasks. Coordinated with multiple Upstream/Downstream teams and external vendors to fix data dependency issues.

**Skills Acquired :** Mainframe, DBMS, DB2.

#### **Certifications**

- Infosys Certified Data Science Practitioner using Python.
- Microsoft Azure Al fundamentals (Al-900).
- Infosys Certified Python & SQL developer.
- Infosys Certified Agile practitioner.
- Infosys Certified Mainframe Associate.
- Cambridge English Entry level Certificate.

#### **Achievements**

- Bagged the Analytics professional/ Open Source Professional & Cloud professional Skilltags from Infosys.
- Got appreciated with the 'Rising Star' badge from Infosys.
- Received appreciations from client for reducing external file dependencies & performing feature enhancement for an internal tool.
- Won second prize on Inter DC Cricket competition.

### **Work Authorization:**

Visa Type	Visa	Country	State	Sponsor
Employment based	H-1B	U.S.A	Oregon	Infosys Ltd

## **Educational Background**

Qualification	Specialization	Institution	Percentage	Y.O.P
B.E	ECE	R.M.K Engineering college, Thiruvallur	84.60	2018
HSE	РСМВ	S.R.K.B.V.M.H.S.School, Kulasekharam	95.01	2014
SSLC	Science-Math	S.R.K.B.V.M.H.S.School, Kulasekharam	94.80	2012

#### **Personal Details**

Nationality : Indian Gender : Male

DOB : 04/07/1997 Father's Name : Kumar K

Permanent Address: 12/246, Odalivilai, Cheruppaloor,

Kulasekharam, Kanyakumari District,

Tamilnadu - 629161

## **Declaration:**

I hereby declare that the above mentioned information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Yours Truly, **Ajaykumar K**